<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on @joepope44</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on @joepope44</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chopped</title>
      <link>/blog/chopped/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/chopped/</guid>
      <description>This week we are looking at data from the Food Network’s cooking show “Chopped”. I decided to focus more on the data analysis portion of the project and just use a simple bar chart for my viz.
I noticed that some contestant records in the data set contained the hometown or home “base” of the Chef. The overwhelming majority are from New York City, perhaps not that surprisingly because of all the restaurants and also that the show is filmed there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endangered Plants</title>
      <link>/blog/endangered-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/endangered-plants/</guid>
      <description>Today we are analyzing extinct and endangered plants for TidyTuesday.
Every week I find myself utilizing the truly excellent site Data-to-Viz by Yan Holtz and Conor Healy for inspiration on what I want to try and learn with R. The site is interactive and helps you figure out the best visualization given numerical or categorical data. It’s well worth a bookmark in your favorite browser.
This week’s data set has three tables, many of which have several columns/features and ways in which to cut up the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avatar: The Last Airbender</title>
      <link>/blog/avatar-the-last-airbender/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/avatar-the-last-airbender/</guid>
      <description>Today we are looking at text data from the scripts for the TV show ‘Avatar: The Last Airbender’.
I decided to see if certain characters that dominate a show, based on their word count, affects the ratings in a postive or negative way. It would be interesting to incorporate screen time as well, but all I have here is word count.
Setup First we setup our enivronment and load the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Ratings</title>
      <link>/blog/coffee-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/coffee-ratings/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;A TidyTuesday project modelling coffee ratings predictions
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>